— AHSAN ZAIDI ←

FULLSTACK WEB DEVELOPER & TECHNICAL SPECIALIST

CONTACT



832-537-2825



zaidiahsan.r@gmail.com



portfolio



LinkedIn

SKILLS

Programming Languages

✓ HTML5, CSS, BOOTSTRAP, JQUERY, JAVASCRIPT, NODE.JS SQL, EXPRESS.JS, SEQUELIZE, REACT

Databases

MYSQL, NO SQL, MONGO DB, **RELATIONAL DATABASES**

Software/Technologies

✓ VS CODE, GITHUB, GITBASH, HEROKU, INSOMNIA, NPM, JSON, JSX, WEB API, SERVER SIDE API, MVP, MVC, ORM, OOP, MS OFFICE, HANDLEBARS, JEST, MONGOOSE, MERN

EDUCATION

University of Texas

(2022)

FullStack Web Developer Certification

University of Texas SA

(2016-2021)

Information Systems

PROFILE

Self-motivated web developer with considerable technical skills in both front and backend development. A quick learner able to play a key role in streamlining existing codebases writing reusable code to encourage efficient workflow. A keen eye for front end development, with a strong desire to improve my existing skillset through experience; Eager and ready to lead into the next step from intern to professional programmer.

EXPERIENCE

Binary Chemist – Web Developer intern

(2021-2022)

At Binary Chemist I was responsible for determining the structure while designing client webpages, which includes developing new user features in reusable blocks of code. Using a variety of markup languages, I was tasked with improving existing codebases; optimizing page load times and maintaining code accuracy through jest testing.

CVS Pharmacy - Shift Supervisor

(2019-2021)

Managed store operations along with shift records, producing timely reports to keep higher management up-to-date. Documenting transactions on a day to day basis to promote inventory accuracy. Coordinated workflow and maintained employee schedules to improve efficiency while assessing team performances to encourage productivity.

PROJECTS

(2021-2022)

- LIBRARY-APP
- **GET-UP EXERCISE**
- WEATHER-APP
- **CODE QUIZ**
- NOTE TAKER
- PROJECT-MGMT

- WORK DAY SCHEDULER
- **SNAKE**
- SOCIAL NETWORK API
- E-COMMERCE BACKEND
- **EMPLOYEE TRACKER**
- **TECH BLOG**